{"name": "65F  2014-6 Asia", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. If  and , then  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Let a function of 2 variables be defined by f(x, y) = xy - (x - y). What is the value of  f(5, 3)?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "8", "C": "13", "D": "17", "E": "23"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. What is the largest value of x for which there exists a real value of y such that x2 + y2 = 144 ?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "72", "C": "132", "D": "144", "E": "288"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. If 11(x - 6) = -12, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. If r = 1, s = -2, and t = 3, what is the value of (r - s)t ?", "choices": {"A": "-9", "B": "-3", "C": "-1", "D": "9", "E": "27"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "16x16", "B": "16x64", "C": "60x16", "D": "60x18", "E": "60x64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Taneisha wants to remodel 3 rooms in her house. She measures the rooms and estimates that she will need 30 square yards of vinyl flooring and 3 gallons of paint. She checks prices at nearby stores for vinyl flooring and paint. To spend as little money as possible to complete the remodeling, Taneisha is willing to buy at more than 1 store. Using Taneisha's estimates and the prices in the chart below, which includes tax, what is the SMALLEST amount of money she can spend to meet her vinyl flooring and paint needs?", "choices": {"A": "$251.34", "B": "$274.62", "C": "$286.17", "D": "$294.99", "E": "$373.17"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. What value of x satisfies the equation  ?", "choices": {"A": "-14", "B": "-12", "C": "-9", "D": "-6", "E": "-4"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. How many terms are in the geometric sequence 3, 6, 12, 24, ....., 192?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7", "C": "8", "D": "189", "E": "192"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. The quadrilateral shown below has a perimeter of 20 inches. Which of the following are the lengths, in inches, of the 4 sides of the quadrilateral?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "3, 4, 6, 7", "C": "5, 5, 5, 5", "D": "6, 7, 9, 10", "E": "7, 8, 10, 11"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Rectangle ABCD is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. Shifting rectangle ABCD 8 coordinate units right and 10 coordinate units down forms a second rectangle, A'B'C'D'. What are the coordinates of B' ?", "choices": {"A": "(3, -6)", "B": "(4, 3)", "C": "(4, -7)", "D": "(4, -13)", "E": "(6, -5)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. A truck stop parking lot has 50 trucks parked in it. There are exactly 10 wheels on some of the trucks; there are exactly 18 wheels on the others. There are 788 wheels altogether on the 50 trucks. How many trucks with exactly 10 wheels are in the lot ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "14", "D": "25", "E": "36"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. What is the area, in square centimeters, of \u25b3ABC shown below?", "choices": {"A": "75", "B": "84", "C": "87.5", "D": "168", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The expression 3(x + 4) - 2(x - 7) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x - 3", "B": "x - 2", "C": "x + 11", "D": "x + 26", "E": "5x + 26"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. What is the slope of any line parallel to the line 5x + 6y = 2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The figure below shows several angles with initial side. The measure of each of these angles is indicated at the end of its terminal side. For example, the measure of \u2220CBP is 30\u00b0 and the measure of \u2220CBM is 150\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220PBN ?", "choices": {"A": "80\u00b0", "B": "89\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "110\u00b0", "E": "140\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  When Tom baby-sits, he charges a fixed fee of $3, plus $4 per hour or part of an hour. What amount would Tom charge to baby-sit for 3 hours and 15 minuted?", "choices": {"A": "$15", "B": "$16", "C": "$19", "D": "$21", "E": "$28"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Given that there are 5,280 feet in 1 mile, what is a speed of 45 miles per hour expressed in feet per minute?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. A CD player that normally sells for $199 is on sale for 30% off. A second CD player that normally sells for $210 is on sale for 35% off. What is the positive difference between the sale prices of the 2 CD players?", "choices": {"A": "$73.50", "B": "$59.70", "C": "$13.80", "D": "$11.00", "E": "$2.80"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. What is the value of -2-3 - (-2)3 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "16"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Phuong drew a square that has sides 4 units long. He divided each side of the square into segments 1, 2, and 1 units long. He then drew lines to form squares, and shaded one of these new squares, as shown in the figure below. What fraction of the area of the original square is shaded?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In the figure below,  AB is parallel to CD; EF intersects AB at P and CD at Q; and the points C, R, Q, and D are collinear. If the measure of \u2220PRO is 55\u00b0 and the measure of \u2220EPA is 60\u00b0\uff0cwhat is the measure of \u2220RPQ?", "choices": {"A": "55\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "65\u00b0", "D": "70\u00b0", "E": "115\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. If , what are the possible values for x ?", "choices": {"A": "-26 and 20", "B": "-20 and 20", "C": "-20 and 26", "D": "-3 and 3", "E": "20 and 26"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The diagram below shows the options available to a traveler who is at the airport and wants to go to a particular hotel. The traveler can take a taxi directly from the airport to the hotel, but taking a train, a bus, or a boat will get her only as far as a station from which she must then take a train, a bus, or a boat to the hotel. For example, 1 option available to her (in addition to taking a taxi) is to take a train from the airport to the station and a boat from the station to the hotel. Another is to take 2 trains. Altogether, how many options for going from the airport to the hotel are available to the traveler?(Note: All travel must be in the direction of the arrow shown on the diagram.)", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "7", "C": "9", "D": "10", "E": "12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The figure below shows a lighthouse built on level ground at sea level. You are standing near its light so your eye level is 180 feet above the ground. From your eye level to a sailboat nearby, the angle of depression is 30\u00b0. About how many feet from the base of the lighthouse is the sailboat?", "choices": {"A": "90", "B": "100", "C": "160", "D": "310", "E": "920"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  In the standard (x, y)coordinate plane, M(7, -8) is the midpoint of TW. If W has coordinates (3, 9), what are the coordinates of T?", "choices": {"A": "(4, -17)", "B": "(4, -7)", "C": "(5, )", "D": "(11, -25)", "E": "(11, 1)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. The 2 circles shown in the figure below are tangent at B, and AB and BD are diameters of equal length. Also, C is on BD; E is on the circle with BD as a diameter; E, B, and F are collinear; and \u2220FAB and \u2220ECD are right angles. Which of the following statements must be true?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "\u2220ADB \u224c \u2220ECA", "C": "EC is a radius.", "D": "\u25b3ABF is similar to \u25b3CED.", "E": "The area of \u25b3BEC is  the area of \u25b3BED."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. If x is a positive number such that , the value of x is:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In \u25b3ACD below, BD bisects \u2220ADC, and 2 angle measures are given. What is the measure of the \u2220BDC?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "50\u00b0", "D": "60\u00b0", "E": "80\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. A store sells $.75 and $.50 candy bars. One day, total candy bar sales were $95, and 20 more $.50 bars were sold than $.75 bars. Which of the following equations gives the number, c, of $.75 candy bars sold?", "choices": {"A": ".75c + .50(c+ 20) = 95", "B": ".75c + .50(c - 20) = 95", "C": ".75(c + 20) + .50c = 95", "D": ".75(c - 20) + .50c = 95", "E": ".75c + 20 + .50c = 95"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. What is the perimeter, in centimeters, of the figure shown below?", "choices": {"A": "42", "B": "60", "C": "66", "D": "84", "E": "134"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The volume, V, of a right circular cone with radius r and height h can be found using the formula . A cone-shaped paper cup has a volume of 142 cubic centimeters and a height of 8.5 centimeters. What is the radius, to the nearest centimeter, of the paper cup?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "8", "D": "12", "E": "16"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. A ladder that is 8.25 meters long is leaning against a vertical wall, as shown in the figure below. The ladder makes an angle of 76\u00b0 with the level ground. Which of the following expressions gives the distance, in meters from the base of the ladder to the base of the wall?", "choices": {"A": "8.25 cos 76\u00b0", "B": "8.25 sin 76\u00b0", "C": "8.25 tan 76\u00b0", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. The mass of a helium nucleus is about 6.64 x 10-27 kg. Written out completely in decimal form, this mass is 0.0...0664 kg. How many zeros follow the decimal point and precede the first 6?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "26", "C": "27", "D": "28", "E": "29"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Given that the domain for x is (-3, -2, -1, 0, 1, 2, 3), what is the complete solution set for 2x + 1 &gt; -1?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Four lateral sides of a rectangular box are formed by folding the cardboard shown below and taping the 2 ends together. Which of the following is closest to the minimum number of square centimeters of additional cardboard needed to add a top and a bottom to the box?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "16", "C": "20", "D": "40", "E": "56"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. A rectangular pond is 4 meters wide and 6 meters long. A flower bed planted all the way around the pond has a uniform width. The area of the rectangular region taken up by the pond and flower bed is 80 square meters. What is the perimeter, in meters, of this region?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "36", "C": "38", "D": "52", "E": "76"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. The charge for having a wood floor refinished by Jan's Janitorial Service is proportional to the area of the floor. Jan's charge for refinishing a rectangular wood floor 10 feet by 20 feet is $100. What is Jan\u2018s charge for refinishing a rectangular wood floor that is 20 feet by 40 feet?", "choices": {"A": "$100", "B": "$200", "C": "$300", "D": "$400", "E": "$600"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. As part of a school field trip, a biology class goes hiking in Appletree Forest. Monique walks 4 miles due north, 7 miles due east, 8 miles due north, and 2 miles due west. What is the straight-line distance, in miles, Monique is from her starting point?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "13", "C": "17", "D": "19", "E": "21"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The ratio of the length of a rectangle to its width is 5:3. The perimeter of the rectangle is 48 cm. What is the width, in centimeters, of the resample?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "6", "C": "9", "D": "15", "E": "18"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.The table below gives information about a 500-room hotel. The hotel has 6 types of rooms: 3 different combinations of beds in both nonsmoking (NS) and smoking (S). The table gives the cost per night per room for each room type. The table also includes the number of rooms of each type for each of the 2 categories of rooms: beachfront (B) and tower (T). (Note: Ignore tax.)41. Which of the following is closest to the percent of the rooms that have 2 queen beds?", "choices": {"A": "18%", "B": "27%", "C": "36%", "D": "46%", "E": "54%"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.The table below gives information about a 500-room hotel. The hotel has 6 types of rooms: 3 different combinations of beds in both nonsmoking (NS) and smoking (S). The table gives the cost per night per room for each room type. The table also includes the number of rooms of each type for each of the 2 categories of rooms: beachfront (B) and tower (T).(Note: Ignore tax.)42. On a night when every room is taken, what is the average cost of a room in the hotel?", "choices": {"A": "$85.00", "B": "$90.00", "C": "$92.36", "D": "$92.65", "E": "$95.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.The table below gives information about a 500-room hotel. The hotel has 6 types of rooms: 3 different combinations of beds in both nonsmoking (NS) and smoking (S). The table gives the cost per night per room for each room type. The table also includes the number of rooms of each type for each of the 2 categories of rooms: beachfront (B) and tower (T).(Note: Ignore tax.)43. An expansion plan for the hotel specifies adding 200 rooms with the room types and categories in the same proportions as they are currently. How many nonsmoking, 1-king-bed-only tower rooms are specified in the expansion plan?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "40", "C": "64", "D": "125", "E": "130"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  A circle in the  standard(x, y) coordinate plane has center (8, -2) and radius 9 coordinate units. Which of the following is an equation of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. How many whole numbers between 1 and 100 are divisible, without a remainder, by all three of the number 2, 3, and 5?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "10", "E": "20"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Let a be a positive real number. As shown in the figure below, a triangle is formed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane by the y-axis, the line y = x, and the line y = a. In coordinate units, what is the perimeter of this triangle?", "choices": {"A": "3a", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. What is the area, in square centimeters, of the largest circle that can be cut from a square 12 cm on a side?", "choices": {"A": "12\u03c0", "B": "24\u03c0", "C": "36\u03c0", "D": "72\u03c0", "E": "144\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. The remainder is 7 when a certain number is divided by 99. What is the remainder when this certain number is divided by 9\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Use the following information to answer question 49-51.The graph below shows a car's speed, s, in feet per second, versus time, t, in seconds.49. Among the following, which is the best model for the car's speed on the interval from 8 seconds to 16 seconds?", "choices": {"A": "s = -10t + 160", "B": "s = -20t + 80", "C": "s = -40t + 80", "D": "s = -40t + 160", "E": "s = 40t + 80"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer question 49-51.The graph below shows a car's speed, s, in feet per second, versus time, t, in seconds.50. Which of the following statements describes what must have happened to the car at about time 8 seconds?", "choices": {"A": "The car stopped moving.", "B": "The car started moving in a different direction.", "C": "The car slid downhill.", "D": "The car's speed started to increase.", "E": "The car's speed started to decrease."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer question 49-51.The graph below shows a car's speed, s, in feet per second, versus time, t, in seconds.51. The area under a speed-time graph between any 2 values of represents the distance traveled during that time interval. For this graph, the area between the s(t) graph and the t-axis represents the total distance traveled. At what time, t seconds. will the car have traveled half the total distance for these 16 seconds?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the graph of the function F(x) = a(x - h)2 + k, where a \u2260 0, is a parabola with vertex at (h, k). What is the distance between the vertices of the parabolas given by f(x) = 2(x - 2)2 - 5 and g(x) = (x - 2)2 + 12?", "choices": {"A": "17", "B": "13", "C": "6", "D": "4", "E": "0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. For 90\u00b0 \u2264 \u03b8 \u2264 180\u00b0, what is the value of sin \u03b8 when tan \u03b8 =  ?", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "-3", "C": "3", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. For all positive integer pairs m and n,  must be:", "choices": {"A": "equal to .", "B": "equal to .", "C": "less than .", "D": "greater than ", "E": "between ."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. A polynomial, f(x), has the following values:f(-2) = -10f(-1) = -6f(0) = -4f(1) = 2f(2) = 18Between which 2 consecutive integers, if any, must f(x) have a zero?", "choices": {"A": "-2 and -1", "B": "-1 and 0", "C": "0 and 1", "D": "1 and 2", "E": "f(x) need not have a zero."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane passes through the point (1, 8) and has a slope of -4. At which point does this line intersect the x-axis?", "choices": {"A": "\uff08-1, 0\uff09", "B": "(0, 4)", "C": "(0, 12)", "D": "(3, 0)", "E": "(33, 0)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Given the function defined below, what is f{f(f(3))}?", "choices": {"A": "-116", "B": "-16", "C": "-4", "D": "1", "E": "9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For any positive integer x, one of the following expressions for n, in terms of x, is always a solution to the complex equationin = 1Which expression is it?", "choices": {"A": "4x", "B": "4x + 1", "C": "4x + 2", "D": "4x + 3", "E": "4x + x"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  For the real number k, the degree measure (4k)\u00b0 equivalent to how many radians? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. When (1 + cos \u03b8) \u2260 0 and sin \u03b8 \u2260 0, which of the following is equivalent to the expression ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "sin \u03b8 + cos \u03b8", "C": "sin \u03b8 + 2 cos \u03b8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}]}